Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair

CONTACT 3501 Saint Paul St E-mail: ngopala2@jhu.edu

INFORMATION Apt. 935 Webpage: https://nithin-gk.github.io/

Baltimore, MD, USA On networks:

in

()

RESEARCH Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Image Restoration Interests

RESEARCH I work on problems in computer vision, more specifically on Image restoration, My re-STATEMENT search primarily focuses on Image restoration and deep generative modelling. Specifically I use generative models for multiple downstream tasks including Image synthesis,

Image editing, Image translation as well as Image restoration

EDUCATION Johns Hopkins University

s Hopkins University

Maryland, USA

Ph.D candidate in Electrical and Computer Engineering

2021-Present

• Key courses: Machine Intelligence, Vision as Bayesian Inference, Probabilistic Machine Learning, Compressed Sensing

• Ph.D advisor: Dr. Vishal M Patel

Indian Institute of Technology Madras

Chennai, India

B. Tech & M. Tech in Electrical Engineering

2015-2020

- Key courses: Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Probability, Statistics and Stochastic Processes, Linear Algebra for Engineers, Probabilistic Graphical Models
- Dual degree Thesis: 'Uncontstrained Dynamic Scene Deblurring for Dual lens Cameras'
- Dual Degree project advisor: Prof. A.N. Rajagopalan

PUBLICATIONS

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Wele Gedara Chaminda Bandara, Vishal Patel, Unite and Conquer: Cross Dataset Multimodal Synthesis using Diffusion Models, Arxiv, 2023

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Kangfu Mei, Vishal Patel, Bi-Noising Diffusion: Towards Conditional Diffusion Models with Generative Restoration Priors, Under review 2022

Wele Gedara Chaminda Bandara, Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Vishal Patel, DDPM-CD: Remote Sensing Change Detection using Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic Models, Arxiv, 2023

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Kangfu Mei, Vishal Patel, AT-DDPM: Restoring Faces degraded by Atmospheric Turbulence using Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic

Models, IEEE WACV 2023

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Vishal Patel, T2V-DDPM: Thermal to Visible Face Translation using Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic Models, IEEE FG 2023

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Kangfu Mei, Vishal Patel, A comparison of different atmospheric turbulence simulation methods for image restoration, ICIP 2022

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Rajeev Yasarla, Vishal Patel, NBD-GAP: Non-Blind Image Deblurring Without Clean Target Images, ICIP 2022

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Rajeev Yasarla Vishal Patel, Confidence Guided Network For Atmospheric Turbulence Mitigation, ICIP 2021

Mahesh Mohan MR, **Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair**, AN Rajagopalan, Deep Dynamic Scene Deblurring for Unconstrained Dual-Lens Cameras, TIP 2021

EXPERIENCE

Vision and Image Understanding Lab, Johns Hopkins University

Graduate Research Assistant

Sept 2020-Present

Research in the department of Electrical and Computer Engineering on Supervised and Semi-supervised Image restoration techniques, advised by Dr. Vishal Patel.

Image Processing and Computer Vision Lab, IIT Madras

Graduate Research Assistant

May 2019-August 2020

Research in the department of Electrical Enginnering on Image restoration techniques focusing on dual lens cameras, advised by Dr. AN Rajagopalan.

AWARDS AND SCHOLASTIC ACHIEVEMENTS

- All India Rank 454 in Joint Engineering Entrance (Advanced) 2015 from over 1.5 million candidates.
- State rank 4 in KEAM 2015 from over 200,000 candidates.
- Awarded certificate for being among the top 0.1% in AISSCE 2015 by Central Board of Secondary Education, India.
- Awarded Kishore Vaigyanik Protsahan Yojana Scholarship 2014, by the Government of India, given to top 1000 from 300,000 candidates to pursure study in Sciences.

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Languages: Python, C++, LATEX

Libraries: PyTorch, TensorFlow, NumPy, OpenCV, Scikit-learn

Applications and tools: Git, MATLAB

Co-Curricular Social Initiatives Activities

- Volunteered for a project aimed at increasing content in vernacular languages in Wikipedia. Contributed around 10 articles for the same. (Sept 2015 April 2016)
- Led a team of 17 students for providing education to under-privileged children in high school. (Sept 2016 April 2017)
- Part of the managerial team of National Service Scheme, India, which oversaw 10 student-run projects. Mentored two projects personally as a member of the "Projects" team. (Aug 2017 Jan 2018)